Muzzammil Hussain

15A Gosha E Ahbab - Tech Society - Lahore - Pakistan | muzzammilz@gmail.com | +92-33-3742-9030

Summary

Passionate, responsible and committed engineer, with a get-it-done, on-time spirit, and more than 11 years experience designing, implementing and adapting technically sophisticated online web applications using LAMP technologies, multi-tier architecture and more. Proficient in **Python/PHP/Javascript** infrastructure, language standards, object modeling technologies and application life cycle management.

Highlights

- Product development
- Relationship management
- Solution architecture
- Cloud identity
- Documentation & reporting

- Enterprise architecture
- Mentoring
- Troubleshooting
- Process improvements
- Change lifecycles

Professional Experience

Worked for 10 different companies/startups under the Arbisoft umbrella from 2010 to present in the North America region.

Solution Architect/Engineering Lead

February 2020 - Present iFinancePay - Fintech platform

Designing the entire architecture for transactions (machine to machine and POS) and automated order execution. Leading the entire team and handling all sorts of technical communication, project management and external partner affairs.

Keywords:

Python, PostgresQL, PHP, MySQL, Javascript, Crypto, 10+ team members

Principal Software Engineer/Solution Architect/Engineering Lead

November 2016 - January 2020 Wanderu - Bus and Train tickets

I worked on a data integration part of the project where we integrate bus and train companies API's to wanderu core network. Developed proof of concepts and designed new architecture. Led a team and expanded Wanderu from North America to Europe.

Keywords:

MongoDB, PostgresQL, Node.js, Reactjs, Scrapy, Twisted, Trec, Python, 20+ team members

Principal Software Engineer/Engineering Lead

January 2016 - November 2016 Travelliance - Flight disrupt solutions

I worked on their new portal which will be used to handle disruptions. This time, not only I worked on the project but also led a team of 10+ team members.

Keywords:

MySQL, Angularjs, PHP, .NET, 10+ team members

Senior Software Engineer

July 2012 - December 2015 InSparq - Social E-commerce

I worked on different modules of that project including but not limited to social widget creations using javascript, creating and maintaining analytics, creating and maintaining pinboard style shopping experience using Javascript and Java.

Keywords:

MySQL, Java, Spring, PHP, Codeigniter, Couch DB, Memcache, Redis, Node.js, jQuery, BackboneJS, AngularJS, 8 team members

Software Engineer

March 2012 - July 2013 Kayak - Travel search results

I worked on creating a javascript based code which is used to autofill the iOS based devices booking forms.

Keywords:

Javascript, Regex, 5 team members

November 2011 - February 2012 LUMS University Portal

My Work was to create and maintain the backend of the portal.

Keywords:

PHP, Drupal, MySQL, jQuery, Apache, 4 team members

August 2011 - October 2011 Kawish - Welfare Trust

My Work was to create and maintain this website entirely.

Keywords:

PHP, MySQL, jQuery, Apache, 2 team members

December 2010 - August 2011 CaliberVantage - HRM System

My Work was to create and maintain a social network using the Elgg framework.

Keywords

.NET, C#, MSSQL, PHP, Elgg, MySQL, Java, Oracle, jQuery, 10 team members

June 2010 - December 2010 MyValidus - Sports Social Network

I worked on different modules of that project including but not limited to admin panel customization, scholarships, messaging, portfolio, workouts, search.

Keywords:

Python, Django, MySQL, jQuery, Apache, 8 team members

April 2010 - June 2010 Manezil - Real Estate Search Engine

I worked on different modules of that project including but not limiting to admin panel creation, property search algorithms.

Keywords

PHP, CakePHP, MySQL, jQuery, Apache, 4 team members

Education

2009 – Masters in Computer Science.

The Islamia University of Bahawalpur. Pakistan.

2007 - Bachelors in Advance Computer Studies.

The Islamia University of Bahawalpur. Pakistan.

2004 - Intermediate in Computer Science

Board of intermediate and secondary education Bahawalpur. Pakistan.